Syracuse Friends of Chamber Music Records
Syracuse Friends of Chamber Music Records
1950-2004
Syracuse Friends of Chamber Music
3 linear ft.
Records from the Syracuse (New York) music society. Clippings, constitution and bylaws, correspondence, financial records, fundraising material, grant applications, minutes, printed material, programs. Includes material related to the organization's 40th anniversary celebration.
2475028
Biographical History
The Syracuse Friends of Chamber Music, founded by Syracuse professor of music and violinist Louis Krasner, has been in operation since 1950. The SFCM brings acclaimed chamber musicians to the H.W. Smith Concert Hall in Jamesville for a series of six concerts each year from October through April. Past performers include the Ying Quartet, Gryphon Trio, Tokyo String Quartet, and Concertante.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Syracuse Friends of Chamber Music Records comprises the files of the Syracuse (New York) music society. It includes clippings, constitution and bylaws, correspondence, financial records, fundraising information, grant applications, minutes, printed material, programs, and audio recordings as well as material related to the organization's 40th anniversary celebration.
Related Material
also has the records of the Syracuse Society for New Music as well as the records of Clark Music Company, a local manufacturer of pianos and organs, and Professor Louis Krasner's Collection of Bookplates and Ephemera.
Subject and Genre Headings
New York State; Music; Syracuse Friends of Chamber Music; Chamber music; Concert programs; Music -- Societies, etc.; Music -- Performance -- New York (State) -- Syracuse; Syracuse (N.Y.) -- Social life and customs; Syracuse (N.Y.) -- Intellectual life; Correspondence.; Financial records.; Programs (documents); Minutes (administrative records); Photographs.; Audiotapes.; Musicians.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Dorothea P. Nelson and Fritz Rohrlich, Syracuse Friends of Chamber Music board members
Inventory
- Audio Recordings
  - Munson-Williams-Proctor Institute: Michala/Hanne Petri, 04/28/1985; sfcm_001; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 1)
  - Ars Musica: The Baroque Orchestra [Pieces 1 and 2], 02/11/1986; sfcm_002; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 1)
  - Ars Musica: The Baroque Orchestra [Piece 3], 04/14/1985; sfcm_003; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 1)
  - Ars Musica: The Baroque Orchestra [Piece 4], 04/14/1985; sfcm_004; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 1)
  - Ars Musica: The Baroque Orchestra [Piece 5 and 6], 04/14/1985; sfcm_005; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 1)
  - Emerson String Quartet - Piece #3, 11/02/1985; sfcm_006; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 1)
  - Emerson Quartet Piece #3, 11/02/1985; sfcm_007; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 1)
  - Cascade Soloists Piece #10, 11/16/1985; sfcm_008; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 1)
  - Cascade Soloists Piece #4, 11/16/1985; sfcm_009; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 1)
  - Juilliard String Quartet - “old” Piece #1 and #2, 04/26/1986; sfcm_010; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 1)
  - Juilliard String Quartet - Piece #2 - Beethoven, 04/26/1986; sfcm_011; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 1)
  - Michala Petri Duo - Pieces #1-3, 03/07/1987; sfcm_012; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 1)
  - The Petri Duo - Pieces #1-4, 03/07/1987; sfcm_013; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 2)
  - Los Angeles Piano Quartet, 03/21/1987; sfcm_014; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 2)
  - Los Angeles Piano Quartet - Piece #3 Brahms, sfcm_015; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 2)
  - Tokyo String Quartet - Part 2 - Pieces #3 and 4, 04/11/1987; sfcm_016; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 2)
  - Tokyo String Quartet - Part 1 - Pieces #1 and 2, 04/11/1987; sfcm_017; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 2)
  - Concerto Soloists: Chamber Orchestra of Philadelphia - Pieces #4 and 5, 10/17/1987; sfcm_018; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 2)
  - Concerto Soloists: Chamber Orchestra of Philadelphia - Pieces #1-3, 10/17/1987; sfcm_019; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 2)
  - Boston Chamber Music Society - Piece #2, 11/14/1987; sfcm_020; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 2)
  - Boston Chamber Music Society - Piece #2, 11/14/1987; sfcm_021; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 2)
  - Mendelssohn String Quartet - Piece #2, 12/05/1987; sfcm_022; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 2)
  - Mendelssohn String Quartet - Piece #1, 12/05/1987; sfcm_023; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 2)
  - Vermeer Quartet - Pieces #1-2, 02/06/1988; sfcm_024; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 2)
  - Vermeer Quartet - Piece #3, 02/06/1988; sfcm_025; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 3)
  - The Painter’s Music, The Musician’s Art, An die Musik [Part 1 and 2], 03/19/1988; sfcm_026; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 3)
  - The Painter’s Music, The Musician’s Art, An die Musik [Part 3 and 4], 03/19/1988; sfcm_027; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 3)
  - Tokyo String Quartet [Pieces #1 and 2], 04/16/1988; sfcm_028; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 3)
  - Tokyo String Quartet [Piece #3], 04/16/1988; sfcm_029; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 3)
  - Takacs String Quartet - Pieces #1-2 [Haydn and Bartok], 03/12/1988; sfcm_030; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 3)
  - Takacs String Quartet - Pieces #2-3 [Bartok and Brahms], 03/12/1988; sfcm_031; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 3)
  - Members of the Juilliard String Quartet with Gilbert Kalish [Piece #1-5], 10/15/1988; sfcm_032; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 3)
  - Members of the Juilliard String Quartet with Gilbert Kalish [Piece #2], 10/15/1988; sfcm_033; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 3)
  - Los Angeles Piano Quartet [Piece #6], 10/21/1989; sfcm_034; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 3)
  - Music Antiqua Koln - Pieces #8-10 [Purcell, Biber, Pachelbel], 10/29/1988; sfcm_035; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 3)
  - Music Antiqua Koln - Pieces #11-14 [Telemann, Bach, Biber], 10/29/1988; sfcm_036; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 3)
  - Musicians from Marlboro - Pieces #4-5 [Beethoven and Shostakovich], 11/12/1988; sfcm_037; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 4)
  - Musicians from Marlboro - Piece #3 [Dvorak], 11/12/1988; sfcm_038; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 4)
  - Buswell-Parnas-Luvisi Trio [Haydn, Zaninelli and Brahms], 01/21/1989; sfcm_039; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 4)
  - Emerson String Quartet - Pieces #1-2 [Schubert and Shostakovich], 09/23/1989; sfcm_040; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 4)
  - Emerson String Quartet - Pieces #4-5 [Beethoven and Haydn encore], 09/23/1989; sfcm_041; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 4)
  - Los Angeles Piano Quartet - Piece #7 [Dvorak], 10/21/1989; sfcm_042; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 4)
  - Buswell-Parnas-Luvisi Trio, 01/21/1989; sfcm_043; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 4)
  - [untitled Syracuse Friends of Chamber Music Tape #1], sfcm_044; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 4)
  - [untitled Syracuse Friends of Chamber Music Tape #2], sfcm_045; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 4)
  - Tokyo String Quartet, 10/27/1984; sfcm_046; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 4)
  - [Tokyo String Quartet], sfcm_047; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 4)
  - [Tokyo String Quartet], sfcm_048; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 4)
  - Emerson Quartet - Musica Viva, sfcm_049; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 4)